diarydirectory.com 2019-07-25

# Home Page - DIARY directory

DIARY directory is an online information service / database for fashion, beauty and lifestyle media companies and individuals – including PRs, brands, influencers, journalists, media titles. Our aim is to help these industry professionals communicate with each other in a targeted manner through the provision of information such as preferred contact information, areas of interest, social media stats. Our aim is to be completely transparent and accessible with listing owners regarding the contact information we are publishing for them.

You can contact us regarding the details we have for you on info@diaryd.com / 020 7724 7770. 

DIARY directory Limited (DIARYdirectory.com) takes seriously our responsibilities regarding the security and privacy of the data we list. We work to ensure that everyone in the DIARY directory database knows that they are in the database, and with what details; knows the purpose of the database; and that we are easily contactable with requests for changes or removal.

This privacy policy applies to our use of any and all Data collected by us or provided by you in relation to your use of the Website. Please read this privacy policy carefully. We will keep this page updated.  

The DIARY directory site is used mainly, but not exclusively, by fashion, beauty and lifestyle press, PRs, marketing departments and associated industries (including but not limited to freelance photographers, representation agencies, industry bodies). 

**Definitions**

  * Data: collectively all information that you submit to DIARY directory Limited via the Website. 
  * Cookies: a small text file placed on your computer by this Website when you visit certain parts of the Website and/or when you use certain features of the Website. Details of the cookies used by this Website are set out in the clause below (Cookies);
  * DIARY directory Limited, or us: DIARY directory Limited, a company incorporated in England and Wales with registered number 07785698 whose registered office is at 102 Crawford Street, London, W1H 2HR;
  * User or you: any third party that accesses the Website and is not either (i) employed by DIARY directory Limited and acting in the course of their employment or (ii) engaged as a consultant or otherwise providing services to DIARY directory Limited and accessing the Website in connection with the provision of such services; and
  * Website: the website that you are currently using, https://www.diarydirectory.com, and any sub-domains of this site unless expressly excluded by their own terms and conditions.

This privacy policy applies only to the actions of DIARY directory Limited and Users with respect to this Website. It does not extend to any websites that can be accessed from this Website including, but not limited to, any links we may provide to social media websites.

Within this policy, "including" is understood to mean "including without limitation"

**Information held**

Any direct contact details and notes included within DIARY directory are done so with the aim of facilitating targeted communication, allowing industry professionals to contact each other and work together – providing contact details for preferred method(s) of contact, and areas of interest and notes to help other industry professionals be targeted / relevant with the information sent / requests. Your contact information is made available to DIARY directory subscribers only. We will retain your details for as long as you are deemed to be working within, and to be relevant to, the industry.  Processing of your data is necessary for the legitimate interests pursued by the controller or a third party.

We may collect Data incuding the following:

  * Name
  * Date of Birth
  * Gender
  * Job Title
  * Profession
  * Areas of editorial interest for media contacts, creatives and industryINFLUENCERS – that our service might better direct relevant connections
  * Contact Information such as email addresses and telephone numbers
  * Social media handles and data including follower numbers, some engagement stats (industryINFLUENCERS section only) and imagery (industryINFLUENCERS section only)
  * IP address (automatically collected)
  * Web browser type and version (automatically collected)
  * Operating system (automatically collected)
  * A list of URLs starting with a referring site, your activity on this Website, and the site you exit to (automatically collected)
  * in each case, in accordance with this privacy policy.

Additionally:

  * Login data used by members accessing DIARY directory, including IP addresses, times of login
  * Transaction data regarding payments made for DIARY directory services
  * No financial data is collected or stored by DIARY directory – all financial data is collected via GoCardless or Stripe

**How we collect your data**

  * DIARY directory collects and verifies all listed data, mainly contact details for professionals working within the fashion, beauty and lifestyle media and marketing industries.
  * The data is mainly provided directly by you / your press office / your team, or from publicly available sources including your website, blog or your public social media profiles including LinkedIn.
  * We do not buy data from third party sources.
  * DIARY directory has a policy to send back a 'front-end profile page link' to a contact at all company entries upon their listing’s creation or following amendment of their details.
  * For company entries, we accept edits and confirmation from team members on behalf of the team (usually on receipt of an email from the same domain as the listing).
  * When adding or editing personal entries (such as freelancers), the listee is made aware of the purpose of their entry in DIARY directory, has a link to verify it, and a clear way to request any changes, or the removal of the entry.
  * We do not add personal details (including home addresses, mobile numbers, personal email addresses) to the DIARY directory database without informed consent of the data owner.
  * Dated back end notes regarding changes made to the listings, and on whose authority, are kept within the database, plus a record of correspondence regarding listings.
  * Requests for listing edits or removal, or a request to see details listed for a company / individual, can be made at any time to any DIARY directory team member, or to [info@diaryd.com](mailto:info@diaryd.com), and we undertake to react promptly and openly.
  * We aim to contact every entry in the DIARY directory database regularly to let them know they are listed and provide an opportunity to see the listing / request full details. 
  * Our regular mailers have clear unsubscribe links. If people unsubscribe from a mailer checking their details, we contact them individually to verify whether they would like to remain in the database. All email bouncebacks from all mailers are checked and amendments / removals made accordingly.

**How your information is used**

For purposes of the **General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)** DIARY directory Limited is the "data controller".

Any or all of the above Data may be required by us from time to time in order to provide you with the best possible service and experience when using our Website. Specifically, Data may be used by us for the following reasons:

  * In order to provide and improve our service to our members, with the aim of facilitating targeted, relevant and efficient communication within the industry.
  * Internal record keeping - including to make notes regarding the DIARY directory team’s interaction with you regarding the data we hold for you, and any amends / confirmations.
  * To manage your DIARY directory membership
  * To create a profile page for you in the DIARY directory industry database – accessible by our members. Your profile is also available to you at any time through a dedicated ‘owner link’ which is only supplied to the direct email address associated with your listing
  * Sending targeted press releases on behalf of selected clients via our DIARY delivers service. All mailings include an unsubscribe link.
  * DIARY directory members may also create their own lists with your data included - all DIARY directory members are reminded to use your data in accordance with GDPR.
  * DIARY directory mailers we may send to you include:  
 
    * the DIARY daily news – sent to all members as part of the provided service, and to all those who sign up through our site / our team to request receipt. Recipients may unsubscribe at any time through the link on each mailer
    * New industry vacancy alerts – sent to recipients who have signed up through our site / requested to be added by the team. Recipients may unsubscribe at any time through the link on each mailer
    * Checking mailer – in order to keep your data accurate, we undertake to contact you at least once a year to allow you to review your data that is made available to our members, and to request removal / changes
    * Occasional mailers to our members, for example to let you know about new services now available to you
    * Occasional marketing / market research mailers to promote and improve our service.

**Third party websites and services**

DIARY directory Limited may, from time to time, employ the services of other parties for dealing with certain processes necessary for the operation of the Website. The providers of such services have access to certain personal Data provided by Users of this Website.

Any Data used by such parties is used only to the extent required by them to perform the services that we request. Any use for other purposes is strictly prohibited. Furthermore, any Data that is processed by third parties will be processed within the terms of this privacy policy and in accordance with the GDPR.

**Links to other websites**

This Website provides links to other websites. We have no control over such websites and are not responsible for the content of these websites. This privacy policy does not extend to your use of such websites. You are advised to read the privacy policy or statement of other websites prior to using them.

**Changes of business ownership and control**

  * DIARY directory Limited may, from time to time, expand or reduce our business and this may involve the sale and/or the transfer of control of all or part of DIARY directory Limited. Data provided by Users will, where it is relevant to any part of our business so transferred, be transferred along with that part and the new owner or newly controlling party will, under the terms of this privacy policy, be permitted to use the Data for the purposes for which it was originally supplied to us.
  * We may also disclose Data to a prospective purchaser of our business or any part of it.
  * In the above instances, we will take steps with the aim of ensuring your privacy is protected.

**Access to your data**

  * We aim to inform all those included in DIARY directory when their details are added / amended. 
  * You are entitled to see the information we have for you.
  * If you are unsure whether your details are included in DIARY directory, please email  your name, and business name if relevant, to info@diaryd.com. We will confirm whether you are included and, if so, email you back a link to your listing, whereupon you can inform us of any changes required. 
  * You can also request to be removed from the DIARY directory database at any time. Upon which we will remove your information from the front end database and keep only such information on record as to allow us not to re-add you.  

**Security**

  * Data security is of great importance to DIARY directory Limited and to protect your Data we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure Data collected via this Website with the aim of ensuring the confidentiality and integrity of the Data.
  * If password access is required for certain parts of the Website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. You must not share your password, either within your team, or externally. Subscriber passwords stored are encrypted. 
  * Data is backed up through our hosting company - an ISO 27001 and ISO 27018 certified cloud provider.
  * We endeavour to do our best to protect your personal Data. However, transmission of information over the internet is not entirely secure and is done at your own risk. We cannot ensure the security of your Data transmitted to the Website.
  * Your personal data is not transferred outside the EU.
  * The DIARY directory team are all made aware of the importance of our data handling.

**Cookies**

  * This Website may place and access certain Cookies on your computer. DIARY directory Limited uses Cookies to improve your experience of using the Website and to improve our range of services. DIARY directory Limited has carefully chosen these Cookies and has taken steps to ensure that your privacy is protected and respected at all times.
  * Before the Website places Cookies on your computer, you will be presented with a message bar requesting your consent to set those Cookies. By giving your consent to the placing of Cookies, you are enabling DIARY directory Limited to provide a better experience and service to you. You may, if you wish, deny consent to the placing of Cookies; however certain features of the Website may not function fully or as intended.
  * This Website may place the following Cookies:
    * Strictly necessary cookies - These are cookies that are required for the operation of our website. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of our website.
    * Analytical/performance cookies - They allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our website when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way our website works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily.
    * Functionality cookies - These are used to recognise you when you return to our website. This enables us to personalise our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region).

  * You can choose to enable or disable Cookies in your internet browser. By default, most internet browsers accept Cookies but this can be changed. For further details, please consult the help menu in your internet browser.
  * You can choose to delete Cookies at any time; however you may lose any information that enables you to access the Website more quickly and efficiently including, but not limited to, personalisation settings.
  * It is recommended that you ensure that your internet browser is up-to-date and that you consult the help and guidance provided by the developer of your internet browser if you are unsure about adjusting your privacy settings.

**General**

  * You may not transfer any of your rights under this privacy policy to any other person. We may transfer our rights under this privacy policy where we reasonably believe your rights will not be affected.
  * If any court or competent authority finds that any provision of this privacy policy (or part of any provision) is invalid, illegal or unenforceable, that provision or part-provision will, to the extent required, be deemed to be deleted, and the validity and enforceability of the other provisions of this privacy policy will not be affected.
  * Unless otherwise agreed, no delay, act or omission by a party in exercising any right or remedy will be deemed a waiver of that, or any other, right or remedy.
  * This Agreement will be governed by and interpreted according to the law of England and Wales. All disputes arising under the Agreement will be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the English and Welsh courts.

**Changes to this privacy policy**

DIARY directory Limited reserves the right to change this privacy policy as we may deem necessary from time to time or as may be required by law. Any changes will be immediately posted on the Website and you are deemed to have accepted the terms of the privacy policy on your first use of the Website following the alterations.

You may contact DIARY directory Limited  (the "data controller") by email at [info@diaryd.com](mailto:info@diaryd.com).

 **18 April 2019**
